14 Cook Ct. Avondale PA, 19311 609-330-5487 (C) email: shawn.wydrzynski@yahoo.com

## **PROFILE**

Musician and educator, respected for professionalism and focus on continual personal growth. Recognized by peers for leadership and by students for respect and enthusiasm on an individual level. Personal, academic and professional interests have developed skills in:

- Extensive vocal training
- Conducting Choirs
- Music History & Theory
- Classroom Management
- Experience in a diverse classroom setting

- Beginning Band and Orchestra
- General Music
- Valuable teaching methodologies
- Differentiated instruction for multiple learning styles

## AWARDS AND RECOGNITION

- West Chester University Graduate (May 2010)
- Selected to be Add B. Anderson's Building Committee Representative (2012-2013)
- Solo Senior Recital Organized event, repertoire, and arranged for the site (February 2009)
- Berkshire Choral Festival Scholarship recipient (2009 & 2010)
- Dean's list recipient
- Eagle Scout recipient from Boy Scouts of America (2001)

#### PRIOR JOB EXPERIENCE

• School District of Philadelphia

Job responsibilities

Contact Information

Add B. Anderson Elementary General Music (2010-Present)

1034 S. 60<sup>th</sup> St.

Philadelphia, PA 19143

(215)471-2903, Principal Kelly Parker

• Wine & Spirits -

Job responsibilities:

• Contact Information:

Clerk 1(2009-2010)

Sales Associate

New Garden Town Square 350 Scarlett Rd Ste 1-3-5 Kennett Square, PA 19348

(610) 925-5400, GM Richard Sibley

## **ACADEMIC CREDENTIALS**

# Masters of Education in Technology, American College of Education

2012-present

Program focuses on the value of technology in educating students. It also promotes teacher leadership and prepares me to lead professional developments to train other teachers how to use technology to increase student achievement. Degree will be achieved in April 2014.

# B.A. Music Education, West Chester University, West Chester, PA

2006 - 2010

Musical specialty – Voice and Music History. Completed 12 credits of private voice lessons and 9 ensemble credits.

- Student Teaching Assignments
  - o Elementary: Caln Elementary
    - Cooperating Teacher: Megan Wright wrightm@coatesville.k12.pa.us
    - Supervisor: William Powers billpowers.music@gmail.com
  - o Secondary: Rising Sun High School
    - Cooperating Teacher: Jeff Anderson jmanderson@ccps.org
    - Supervisor: William Powers billpowers.music@gmail.com

# CAMPUS ~ COMMUNITY ~ VOLUNTEER COMMITMENTS

#### School Activities

- Building Committee Representative 2012-2013
- Developed a choir, grades 4-7
- Developed a bucket drumming club
- Direct music for musicals
- School talent show recruitment and advisor
- Started an after school hockey club

# West Chester University

- Men's Choir 2006-2007
- Mastersingers Audition Choir 2007-2008
- Concert Choir Audition Choir 2008-2010
- Members of Pennsylvania Music Educators Association
- Member of American Choral Directors Association
- PMEA Conference Attendee 2007-2009

# **REFERENCES:**

Mr. Kelly Parker (Current Principal/Add B Anderson) Kparker@philasd.org

215-694-2166

Dr. David DeVenney (Choral Studies/W.C.U.)

ddevenney@wcupa.edu

610-436-2952

Barbara Schwartz (Teacher Coach/Philadelphia)

Bbschwartz1@msn.com

Megan Wright (Caln Elementary/ Co-op)

wrightm@coatesville.k12.pa.us